<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-01-18T22:51:34+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Domingos de Eulária Dumba</title><subtitle>Data Scientist</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Data Science on Perspective: the forgotten article of William S. Cleveland</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2025/01/29/post.26.1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Science on Perspective: the forgotten article of William S. Cleveland" /><published>2025-01-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2025/01/29/post.26.1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2025/01/29/post.26.1.html"><![CDATA[<p>As I am writing, January 8 2026, it has passed 25 years since the first publication of “Data Science: An Action Plan for Expanding the Technical Areas of the Field of Statistics”. This paper, as David Donoho pointed out, may be the earliest and clearest mention to Data Science as a new field for addressing the emphasis on theory given by most of the statisticians.
In the last years, a new question that may pose now may be whether being a Data Scientist is still relevant given the rise of ML Engineering roles, with many of the promoters of such conversations stating, “Nobody cares anymore about a professional that simply runs notebooks”. Clearly, such statements are not well received by those acquainted</p>

<p>Two trends are clear for me: during the boom of the Data Scientist role (2010), traditional statisticians stated</p>]]></content><author><name>Domingos de Eulária Dumba</name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I am writing, January 8 2026, it has passed 25 years since the first publication of “Data Science: An Action Plan for Expanding the Technical Areas of the Field of Statistics”. This paper, as David Donoho pointed out, may be the earliest and clearest mention to Data Science as a new field for addressing the emphasis on theory given by most of the statisticians. In the last years, a new question that may pose now may be whether being a Data Scientist is still relevant given the rise of ML Engineering roles, with many of the promoters of such conversations stating, “Nobody cares anymore about a professional that simply runs notebooks”. Clearly, such statements are not well received by those acquainted]]></summary></entry></feed>